welcome to meditating with John for a
key
we do this every weekday morning at 9:30
a.m. Eastern Time
Mondays we alternate between a pie a day
which is a review of the whole ecology
practices orbits going to do today and a
Dharma day in which I teach a new
principle of practice that builds on
previous principles and practices if
you're joining us for the first time
welcome go to the notes in the
description you'll find links to
previous lessons and previous sets I
recommend immediately doing less than
one and then you can join with us and
keep practicing and then do one of the
new do a new lesson every Saturday or
Sunday and eventually you'll catch up
with us it would be helpful if you could
all like this stream to increase the
visibility you two algorithm so I can
help as many people as possible with
this at the end of every session there
is Q&A please limit your questions to
the current course ecology of practice
although you can ask questions from any
of the lessons for more general
questions please come to the general Q&A
livestream we do on YouTube every third
Friday of the month at 3:00 p.m. Eastern
it will be July 17th this month okay so
let's get into position I'm going to
stand sign on again just to give you a
reminder how we get into guchi our toes
are pointing forward they're not splayed
out like this so they're not like this
they're like this and then my feet about
shoulder width apart I'm going to tuck
my coccyx in as if I'm sitting down I
put my hands out and I roll my shoulders
down spread my palms and my hands drop
beside me now getting into Wu Jie
position all right
this is straight here but not tense or
tight belly is loose eggs under the
armpit okay so I'm going to stand a
little side on hopefully that will help
okay so we're gonna come in to our first
judge on
and so we're caught a big ball here and
we're squeezing the ball in squeezing it
towards our chest where's the big ball
we're squeezing between our legs and
we're squeezing we're sitting on it
and we're doing four breaths
now here bring your hands together
inhale and then squeezing another ball
bring your hands in and four breaths
baby breaths fire in the belly
okay Elissa sphincter muscle come here
microcosmic or about old men stroking
the beard
reciprocal opening
the R&R
[Music]
[Applause]
dealing the silk so inhaling to the lot
excellent to the right remember I'm
turning my hips right as I shift my
weight my my head turns because my hip
terms
I'm not turning from my head I'm turning
from my hands like I'm reeling silk and
then when I do it if my mind is trying
to be soft and supple and smooth and
subtle so to slow it down
I want to suffuse my mind through my
body and my body through my mind so I
feel like I'm shiny and then I sing I
draw up everything I drop into that
self-organization and I let it take on
life of its own
reeling the soap
come back to Wu ji bring down the
heavens inhale down the front inhale on
the back inhale the core inhale all
three at once
and back into a G position okay let's
sit jason'll for just a camera
okay and it's your basic posture how to
use your intuitive sense of your Center
here you can heads-up open your eyes
ah
you know the final point again speak to
my little tongue here
whatever in drain with a big in breath
no bra bring your mind here you don't
have to do your hands I've just
indicated with my hands what's happening
so is a head you know exhale drop to the
center of my skull
all three direct all 360 direction throw
heart center of the chest
it's a little plexus
don't ya
rude
cp3 creator to the earth
in your practice
slowly what if you practice trying as
best you can obtain to be able to
cultivate it in your practice the other
day the consciousness cognition
character and communitas perhaps by
reciting the five promises to yourself
so we'll move into lectio divina suck
the intense
this is from that child maggot birth a
fish cannot round in water where it does
not fall in air the fire of creation
goal does not vanish the fire brightens
each creature God made must live in its
own true nature how could I resist my
nature that lives from oneness with God
so this very elusive for me there's a
lot of associations coming up but
they're all sort of mingling and merging
about I got that sense that she's trying
through this image to call me and the
one that's getting most was the first
line of fish not drown in water there's
a deep relationship here and what's what
I'm associating that with is something
that's normally so presuppose so in the
background again so foundational it's
very it's almost invisible but to
remember to realize so there's I she's
trying to point out that our
relationship to being the ground of
being to God is like relationship of the
fish to water
so what does that mean trying to click
so I'm picking up on that resonating
with what does that mean getting an
inkling of it it's not very clear in
that sense so try then almost now
imagine myself as a fish in the water
we can't be like what's up and then then
I get a sense of this is helic what is
it like almost invisible
I see all the beings all the things of
the world I'm not aware of being just
like the fish is seeing all the things
in the water it's not aware of the water
and how the water is sustaining it
giving it life trying to remember that
remember that season and then as I start
to remember I get that last line there's
the fish in the water I long to be one
with this I can't even put all that he
uses the image what is it that longing
that's a remember so remembering being
and I long to be more with one one with
it what would it be like to live in that
remembrance all the time how would I see
the world how would I be in the world
now that I'm swimming in the ocean of
being would that be like there's not a
man for me I feel that I gotta let go of
that almost innate greed to grab and to
hold and to possess oh that's the trust
fish hand round the bird can't fall
that's the trust she's
this is from a Booya dude
oh honey one of the Sufi masters the
inner realm Oh think about how this is
resonating the first reading we eat in a
while we're neither good nor evil exists
both of them belong to the world of
created beings in the presence of unity
there is neither command nor prohibition
oh I can feel this empanada between this
reading in the previous reading be in a
realm where neither good or evil exists
not because we shouldn't think about
those but both of them belong to the
world of created beings and the presence
of unity there is neither command or
prohibition again all the good things
are right the good and bad happened to
the fish but it all happens in the water
in being the unity there and you're
beyond beyond well those two the two
meetings are really resonating for me
getting very deeply into the second one
I could just sense of oneness the unity
that's beyond good and evil up beneath
beyond release the trust the realization
for its own sake
so unfortunately I have a heart out for
today and there is a question that I
need to end right now but I want to
acknowledge any chemistries question in
Indy I'm committing to answer your
question
first thing tomorrow do or in the QA
it's an important question so I want to
give it or rush it I want to give it
careful time in response and give it the
seriousness and the depth that it
requires so we will come back to that
question first off in our Q&A tomorrow I
want to thank you everybody for joining
I want to especially thank like your
friend of techno major bar I'm a lot of
fun Jake I'm a little bit son Jason is
going to see making things happen please
subscribe to this channel to be notified
of the next video we'll also find links
to the lecture series awakening from the
media crisis the dialogo series voices
with rebecky exploring these themes and
depth and sending them in situating them
within a more encompassing way of being
please invite others who might benefit
by sharing this series
Brett is here please join the discord
server right amazing community there are
people who sit through the practices
discussion at large very important the
link is in the description minor we're
doing this every weekday morning at 9:30
Eastern Time this Wednesday is a holiday
in Canada it's a can of a day so there
will be no I will not be here July the
first a little vino sitting July the
first visits on holiday so please
remember that continuity of practice is
more important than share quantity of
practice there is no enemy worse than
your own mind and body no friend no Ally
no true companion on the path which is
greater than your own mind and body
he lamps unto yourselves and to each
other
take good care everyone
see you tomorrow